urbian.org 2008-12-19

# urbian.org - privacy

| 

**Urbian, Inc. Privacy Policy**

**This policy is effective as of 2nd April 2008**

Urbian, Inc. (“Urbian” or “we”) operates and manages the Urbian.org website (the “Urbian Website”), and this Privacy Policy describes Urbian’s use and sharing of personal information, i.e. your full name, email address, mailing address, telephone number, or credit card number, that Visitors and/or Members (“Users”) voluntarily provide to Urbian when they register or visit the Urbian Website. This Privacy Policy applies to all services offered by Urbian, including the Urbian Website, the Urbian Website internet messaging service, the Urbian mobile application software (the “Urbian software”), and any other features, content, or applications offered from time to time by Urbian in connection with the Urbian Services (collectively, the “Urbian Services”). Urbian Services are hosted in the United States.

**1\. AGE LIMITATIONS**  
Urbian does not knowingly allow anyone under the age of 16 to register for the Urbian Services nor does Urbian knowingly collect or solicit personal information from such persons. If you are under 16, please do not attempt to register for any of the Urbian Services, provide any personal information on the Urbian Website, or send any information about yourself to Urbian, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address.  
In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 16, such information will be deleted as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 16, please contact us at privacy@urbian.org.

**2\. MODIFICATIONS**  
From time to time Urbian may modify this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in the industry, in the law, in the collection and use practices of personal information, or in the features, services, and technology offered by Urbian. Any such modifications shall be effective upon the posting of any updated Privacy Policy by Urbian on the Urbian Website. Your continued use of any of the Urbian Services after the posting of such updated Privacy Policy signifies your acceptance of the updated Privacy Policy. It is important that you review this Privacy Policy regularly to ensure you are aware of any updates.

**3\. DISCLAIMERS**  
Any information posted on your profile or any other photos, profiles (including your name, image, and likeness), messages, notes, files, text, information, music, musical works, works of authorship, sounds, video, advertisements, listings, and any other materials (collectively “User Content”) that you upload, publish or display (hereinafter, "post") on or through the Urbian Services or the Urbian Website is posted at your own risk, and such information may become publicly available. We cannot control the actions of other Users you choose to add as Contacts or with whom you may choose to share your profile and information. We cannot and do not guarantee that unauthorized persons will not view your profile or User Content posted on the Urbian Website, and we are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Urbian Website. You understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of User Content may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other Users have copied or stored your User Content.  
Any user located in the European Union is responsible for ensuring that any of their User Profile Information that will be available to the public conforms to any and all local data protection laws. Urbian is not responsible for User Profile Information under the EU local data protection laws.

**4\. INFORMATION OBTAINED BY URBIAN**

**4.1 USER PROFILE INFORMATION**  
When you register on the Urbian Website, you may set up your personal profile, add Contacts, add Places, send messages, perform searches and queries, form groups, set up events, create blogs, track User history, upload documents and other files, and transmit information through various channels. We collect this information in order to provide you service and personalized features. **When you update information, we usually keep a backup copy of the prior version for a reasonable period of time to enable reversion to the prior version of that information.**  
Your user profile contains any information you choose to make available to other Urbian users by adding them as Contacts, including such information as your Urbian user name, full name, nickname, address, telephone numbers, gender, date of birth, employment information, relationship status, photos, location, email address, websites, blogs, school information, political orientation, religious views, hobbies and interests, and any other information that you decide to make available, (collectively “User Profile Information”). You control your user profile, and Urbian does not exercise any control over your User Profile Information. Urbian therefore cannot guarantee that such information will always be available or accessible.

**4.2 PERSONAL INFORMATION**  
Urbian may gather and process information about you, including, but not limited to:  
    Identification data (name, date of birth, address, telephone number, email address etc.)  
    Demographic information (e.g. age, sex, country of residence etc.)  
    Electronic identification data (addresses IP, cookies, etc.)  
    Financial information (credit card information, account number, etc.)  
    Traffic and usage information  
    Products or services ordered and delivered  
    Photographs and video and sound recordings  
    List of your Contacts  
    Information voluntarily submitted to Urbian in connection with any sweepstakes, contests, and surveys, or in connection with requests for products, services, newsletters, or information.  
Urbian may also collect information about you from other sources, such as blogs, messaging services, and other Urbian users in order to provide a more personalized experience.

**4.3 COOKIES**  
When you visit or register on the Urbian Website, your browser type and IP address are stored by Urbian. Urbian also stores certain information from your browser using “cookies,” pieces of data stored on a User’s computer used for authenticating, tracking, and maintaining specific information about that User and storing User preferences.  
Urbian uses session ID cookies to confirm that users are logged in, and which terminate once the browser is closed. Urbian uses a persistent cookie that stores your login ID (but not your password) to make it easier for you to login when you return to the Urbian Website. **You can remove or block this cookie using the settings in your browser if you want to disable this convenience feature.**  
Third party advertisements displayed on the Urbian Website may also contain cookies set by those third party Internet advertisers. Urbian does not control the cookies of these third parties. Urbian Users should review the privacy policy of such third party Internet advertiser to determine how they use cookies.   
You can change your computer settings to alert you each time a cookie is being sent, to block third party cookies, or to block all cookies. Please be aware that by blocking all cookies, you may not have access to certain features on the Urbian Website.

**5\. USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION OBTAINED BY URBIAN**  
Urbian will only use a user’s personal and profile information, whether obtained directly from the user or from a third party source, in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.  
By registering at the Urbian Website, you are consenting to the transfer and processing of your personal information and data in the United States and internationally.  
Any improper collection or misuse of information provided on the Urbian Website is a violation of this Privacy Policy and the Urbian Terms of Use. All violations should be reported to privacy@urbian.org.

**5.1 USE OF PROFILE INFORMATION**  
Your User Profile Information, as defined in Section 4.1 above, is accessible to and may be edited by you, and can be viewed by any Urbian user you add as a Contact. In addition, information such as nickname, photo, age, gender, location, and last login date and time (collectively “Limited Profile”) can be viewed by any Urbian user.  
Other Urbian users may view your Limited Profile by searching for your name, surname, nickname and/or email address or as a result of an Introduction by another Urbian user.

**5.2 MESSAGES/ALERTS FROM URBIAN**  
Urbian may send you service-related email alerts from time to time if, for example, a Contact sends you a message, an Introduction to another Urbian user or Group, a Group Invitation, a Contact Request, and an Event Invitation.  
Urbian may also send you email alerts concerning promotional materials, such as notifications of new Urbian services. You can choose to not receive such alerts by turning off notifications under the settings tab. Urbian reserves the right to send you **notices about your account even if you opt out of all voluntary email notifications.**  
If you choose to use our invitation service to tell another person about the Urbian Website, we will ask you for that person’s email address or other contact information necessary to send the invitation. Urbian will automatically send a one-time email or instant message inviting him or her to visit the Urbian Website. Urbian stores this information to send this one-time invitation, to register a contact addition if your invitation is accepted, and to track the success of Urbian’s referral program. Your friend may contact us at office@urbian.org to request that we remove this information from our database.

**5.3 USER INFORMATION SHARED WITH THIRD PARTIES**  
Urbian may share your User Profile Information with third parties in order to collect information about the popularity of a product/service and to provide you with customized and personalized advertisements and promotions. Such sharing occurs in order for Urbian to provide the Urbian Services free of charge, and will only occur where it is reasonably necessary to provide the Urbian Services, where required by law, or where we have obtained your consent.   
Urbian will not disclose any identification data as defined in Section 4.2 above to any third parties or provide your contact information to any third parties without your consent. Urbian prohibits any third party from sharing your User Profile Information with any other third party and from using such information for any other purpose. **Traffic and demographic information** may also be shared with third party advertisers and business affiliates.  
In the event that ownership of all or substantially all of Urbian, Inc., or businesses owned by Urbian, Inc., changes, your User Profile Information and personal information may be transferred to the new owner so the service can continue operations. In the event of any such transfer, you will be notified of any material changes to the pre-existing Urbian Privacy Policy.

**5.4 USE OF INFORMATION BY URBIAN EMPLOYEES**  
Urbian employees, agents and contractors may obtain access to your personal information if it is necessary in order to provide or maintain the Urbian Services. Outside contractors, agents or affiliates may temporarily store your information on their servers, but their use of the information will be restricted to the specific service for which they were contracted.  
Urbian may also provide your personal information to third parties where you have chosen to receive certain information and the receipt of such information requires the sharing of your personal information.

**6\. THIRD PARTY LINKS & ADVERTISEMENTS**  
The Urbian Website may contain links to other websites. Urbian is not responsible for the privacy practices of those web sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by Urbian.  
Advertisements that appear on the Urbian Website are sometimes delivered directly to you by third party advertisers. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. These third party advertisers may use other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content. Doing this allows the advertising network to recognize your computer each time they send you an advertisement in order to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content. In this way, they may compile information about where individuals using your computer or browser saw their advertisements and determine which advertisements are clicked.

**7\. URBIAN MOBILE APPLICATION**  
In addition to the above, the Urbian Mobile Application also collects such information as: when users meet other users and where, messages sent to other users, messages left for other users, introductions, requests for new contacts, blog postings, information and pictures transferred or uploaded from the Urbian Mobile Application to the Urbian Website, events created on the Urbian Website and transferred to the Urbian Mobile Application. Such information is utilized both for operational reasons, to run and execute the Urbian Services, as well as for marketing purposes. 

**8\. UPDATING INFORMATION**  
Access and control over most personal information on the Urbian Website is readily available through the profile editing tools. Urbian users may modify or delete any of their profile information at any time by logging into their account. Information will be updated immediately. Individuals who wish to deregister their Urbian account may do so on the Settings page. Removed information may persist in backup copies for a reasonable period of time but will not be generally available to Urbian users.  
Where you make use of the communication features of the service to share information with other individuals on Urbian, such as sending a personal message to another Urbian user, you generally cannot remove such communications.

**9\. TERMS OF USE, NOTICES AND REVISIONS**  
Your use of the Urban Services, and any disputes arising from it, is subject to this Privacy Policy as well as our Terms of Use and all of its dispute resolution provisions including arbitration, limitation on damages and choice of law. We reserve the right to change our Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use at any time. Non-material changes and clarifications will take effect immediately, and material changes will take effect within 30 days of their posting on this site. If we make changes, we will post them and will indicate at the top of this page the policy's new effective date. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or through notice on our home page. We encourage you to refer to this policy on an ongoing basis so that you understand our current privacy policy. Unless stated otherwise, our current privacy policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account.

**10\. CONTACTING THE WEB SITE**  
If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please contact us at privacy@urbian.org. 

|
